(Translated with Google Translate!)

AAD (Auto Anime Decomb) Manual

Author: diseac / Version: 0.1.5a (090707) / Environment: Avisynth 2.5.x, YV12/YUY2
Published Address: http://www.nmm-hd.org/bbs/thread-667-1-1.html (nmm Forum)

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

AAD Profile:

AAD is designed specifically for the cartoon, IVTC and deinterlacing with Avisynth script.
In IVTC aspect, AAD using the optional style 4pass processing mode, complementary AADivtc original script, support automatic
processing, while supporting manually write TIVTC the ovr file. Clean and beautiful 3rdpass +4 thpass make gradual scene drawing
wiped out, you no longer need to manually adjust the staggered residual gradient section. AAD's 3pass speed limit mode is slow,
but is particularly effective when the screen is no drawing against extreme Bad Edit.

If you find that in the course of BUG, or have suggestions for me, please contact me or thread here: 17genius@163.com

Thank Avisynth dll plugin developers and producers, thank nmm forum friends I made this script to bring help and inspiration!

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Plug-ins used:
TIVTC v1.0.5 Author: tritical
a60224 040315 Author: chi-yo black
TDeint v1.1 Author: tritical
nnedi2 v1.3 Author: tritical
TMM v1.0 Author: tritical
Vinverse dll version Author: tritical & Didée

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Grammar:

The main function:
AAD (int "mode", bool "tff", string "ovr", bool "debug", bool "ivtc2pass", bool "ivtc3pass", bool "finalpass", bool "ultimate")

Additional independent functions:
AADTrim (int "stf", int "edf", string "func", string "func2", clip "clip1", clip "clip2")
AUS720 (int "a", int "w", int "d", int "s")

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Parameter Description

The first part, the main function: AAD() parameter table

mode = 0/1/2 (integer, default: 1)
AAD processing mode.

0 - Output tfm log file will generate a file named tfm_log.txt sources in the same directory. This option only log output,
please do not use the whole piece independent mode = 0 option.
1 - Selectable 4pass processing mode IVTC, in IVTC regard, I recommend this option.
2 - Selectable 3pass processing mode IVTC, use the original script: AADivtc.

About AADivtc, in theory, that it is my original algorithm. Because first I thought it was out, and secondly, I did not see
anyone else had this operation. But actually help the IsCombedTIVTC() and tdecimate() These two functions are provided by an
external plug-in was implemented, it can not be regarded as an original full sense of it.

AADivtc serve AAD (mode = 2), although I have created an independent function, but please do not use it independently.

Its algorithm is very simple, but if you're lucky, it can reach 100% correct match, and will not appear jerk phenomenon.

But this is only the ideal situation, in practice, it is essential to keep only 60 % accuracy.

In avisynth where I have no way to use more advanced algorithms, so AADivtc now very simple, but sometimes it may be the
perfect solution to some of the more stubborn drawing. When setting mode = 2, by () to perform AADivtc 1st pass, 2nd pass
will be forced to close, ovr is no longer in force, but the 3rd pass the 4th pass can still proceed.

Please note that if you do set: AAD (mode = 2, ivtc3pass = false, finalpass = false), which is exactly equivalent to AADivtc()
streaking, I strongly do not recommend you to do so. Maybe you observe mode = 2 deal out of the movie will not find it there is
something wrong, but I suggest you do not use mode = 2 option on the entire piece. mode = 2 is designed with the mode = 1 is
designed to complement, if you use mode = 1 and found there a short order you are not satisfied, you can try mode = 2, if you
think it's better, you can use this section the frame is a frame to replace you are not satisfied.

Built-in functions AADTrim can easily be done, following a script shows how to simply deal with the mode = 1 the first frame
10-20, and 30-40 frames processed replaced mode = 2.

mode2 = last.AAD (mode = 2)
AAD (mode = 1). AADTrim (10,20, clip1 = mode2). AADTrim (30,40, clip1 = mode2)

tff = true / false (Boolean, default value: true)
true for the odd field first (tff), false to even field first (bff).
* Note: Boolean parameter when set to true (true), said opening, false (false) that is closed, the same below.

debug = true / false (Boolean, default value: false)
Debug mode. Will open and display processing information tfm AAD on the screen, and the output of the debug information tfm
(available DebugView software to view).
Please note that if you just want tablet, do not open this option, otherwise you will be marked with subtitles good pressure
on the film.

finalpass = true / false (Boolean, default value: true)
Final pass operation, kill the residual staggered, staggered on the gradient residual particularly effective scene, but does
not destroy progressive frames. The operation is fully automatic, you do not need to manually Trim (start, end) to clean up
the scene of staggered gradient. Effective time when the ultimate = false. However, if the previous step residual entity
staggered, finalpass may not solve the problem for you. This parameter is recommended to open.

ovr = "x:\xx\xx.txt" (string, default value: "noovr")
Tfm's ovr file specified, valid when mode = 1. When ovr is specified, tfm anyway be placed 1st pass position, even ovr
there nothing to write. If you do not specify ovr, then a60224 will be placed 1st pass the default position. You can set
ovr = "noovr" to temporarily close ovr, to facilitate debugging. When mode = 2, regardless of whether you specify ovr, it
will not take effect. ovr wording see TIVTC manual, nmm forum this post (Author: dgwxx) at the same time be helpful to you.

ivtc2pass = true / false (Boolean, default value: true)
2nd pass IVTC operation. Mode = 1 is valid when. Recommended opened.

ivtc3pass = true / false (Boolean, default value: true)
3rd pass IVTC operation. Effective when mode = 1/2时. Recommended opened.

ultimate = true / false (Boolean, default value: false)
IVTC limit mode, the field is no match for full -frame motion detection alpha blending, valid when ivtc3thpass = true, and
it will be canceled finalpass. Please note that only part of the movement interlaced image will appear during the ghosting
after alpha blending, the backcourt is not the right match ghosting. Advantages limit mode is Deinterlace rate can reach 100%,
the drawback is the screen will have some vague, but the speed is very slow, it will take longer time coding.

The second part, an additional independent functions: AADTrim() parameter table

stf / edf (integer, default: none)
Start frame / end frame.
Almost equal Trim() syntax. But AADTrim (0,0) is represented by the first 0 instead of from 0 to the last frame, which is
AADTrim with Trim only difference in the figures. Because you do not need to use this function to apply to all operating
functions of the film frame. Note, AADTrim are not really cut off the movie, but the movie segments connected together and
then processed. stf / edf is a mandatory parameter must be filled.

func / func2 (string, default: none)
Custom action function.
func parameter defines the operation of the function will be applied to the edf from stf part ; func2 parameter defines the
operating functions will be applied to the outside from stf edf part. You must ensure through your defined function operation
since the frame rate (fps), frame resolution (x & y), and the color space to be connected with other parts of the same,
otherwise the film is not connected in series. Custom manipulation functions, including functions which can and can not have
other things, such as func2 = "last.warpsharp()" is not the correct wording. func and func2 parameters are optional parameters,
you can not fill.

clip1 / clip2 (movie clips, default: none)
Movie clips for replacement.
Clip1 parameters introduced by the movie clip will be replaced from stf to edf part ;
Introduced by the clip2 parameter will replace part of the movie clip from stf to edf outside.
If you specify a func parameter clip1 replaces the partial edf from stf, and then complete the replacement specified by this part
of the parameters to the function func application; If you specify func2 parameter clip2 to be replaced from the rear portion edf
than stf, and then complete the replacement specified by this part of the parameters to the application function func2.
clip1 and clip2 are optional parameters, you can not fill.

The third part, the additional independent functions: AUS720() parameter table

a / w / d / s (integer, default: 0)
Upsize before trimming the number of rows.
Corresponding keyboard a, w, d, s direction, representing the left, top, right, trimming the number of internal trimming line
under, and Resize filter, these figures are equivalent to Upsize cut off before.
For example AUS720 (8,0,8,0) can be equivalent to LanczosResize (1280,720,8,0, -8,0).

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

AAD use examples

IVTC:
AAD()

Tfm output log file:
AAD(mode=0)

Use tfm's ovr:
AAD(ovr="x:\xx\xx.txt")

Debug mode:
AAD(debug=true)

Use AADTrim different movie clips using different filters Sharpen:
AADTrim (100,200,"warpsharp()","UnsharpMask()")

AUS720 simple to use, for example:
AUS720(8,0,8,0)

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Update records

2009-07-07 v0.1.5a

Nnedi plug-in is no longer used, use nnedi2.

2009-01-27 v0.1.5

Cancel AAD main function parameters: top2px. Now no longer supports the shield DVD AAD top of the screen a 2 pixel black border.
3rdpass optimized algorithms, ultimate argument is no longer a tasteless, but still slow down encoding speed.
With the progress of science and development, and now more and more monitor resolution, DVD's screen size has become increasingly
unable to meet the needs of the audience. So I added a new function independently: AUS720(), this function can be achieved simply
upsampling DVD screen resolution to 1280x720.

2008-08-21 v0.1.4

Increase the use of new non- independent functions: AADivtc().
The second way to increase IVTC: mode = 2.
AAD error corrected color space issue information.
To AADTrim increased clip1 parameters.

2008-08-21 v0.1.3

Increase independent function: AADTrim()

2008-08-20 v0.1.2

After much weigh, I finally decided to a60024 on 1st pass position.
Now you can still manually written ovr file specified when ovr exist, tfm will automatically swap deal with a60024 order.
As long as you specify ovr, even ovr there nothing to write, tfm will occupy the 1st pass position.
Add new parameters: ivtc2pass. Now you can set ivtc2pass = false to turn off the 2nd pass.
In order to facilitate future updates, I decided not to use the mode = 2 option to turn debug mode.
Restore the debug parameter when you specify debug = true, you will see AAD information, and tfm information on the screen
(in the tfm be used and not Drop the case)
Part of the parameter name be adjusted.

2008-08-20 v0.1.1

Remove Parameters: debug, increase mode = 2 option.

2008-08-19 v0.1.0

AAD was born !